<?xml version="1.0"?>
<sections>
	<!-- Beginning of Section Encounters -->
	<section id="section0">
	<title>Encounters</title> <!-- Main menu title -->
	<image>assets/story/section_title_one.png</image> <!-- used for section image title on bottom -->

	<slides>
		<!-- each section should have 4 slides with this data-->
		<!-- Beginning of Slide Native Lands -->
		<slide id="slide0-0" anchor="0"><!-- used for first slide that is just an image, -->
			<image>
				<file>assets/panels/story_encounters_00.jpg</file>
			</image>
		</slide>
		<slide id="slide0-1" anchor="1">
	        <title>Native Lands</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
	        <heading>What connects a people and a place?</heading>
	        <description><![CDATA[
				<p>Some Pueblo people in New Mexico today live where Spanish explorers
	            first encountered their ancestors more than 450 years ago. Oral histories that
	            sacred ones and ancient leaders brought them to this place, after travels of thousands
	            of years, through trials and dangers. The pueblos they occupy today, and the lands
	            around them, were given to their ancestors as the place on earth where they were
	            meant to live. Here they learned to plant and harvest corn, to live on their
	            lands in a balanced way, and to remain in this place forever. Pueblo people have
	            stayed in present-day New Mexico through encounters with Navajos (Diné),
	            Apaches (Inde), Comanches (Numunuh), Utes, Texans, Spanish and Mexicans, and
	            finally settlers from the United States. Many of these people drew boundaries
	            on the Pueblo homelands or claimed traditional Pueblo lands as their own. But
	            boundaries divide things, and the Pueblos cannot be separated from this place.</p>
			]]></description>
			<quote><![CDATA[
				<p>"Your father...made you, and it is he who has made the world,
				the sun which you have seen, sky and many other things which you will see."</p>
			]]></quote>
	        <map id="1">
				<title>Native Lands</title>
	        	<image><file>assets/map/map_01.png</file></image>
	        </map>
	        <slideshow id="slideshow0-1">
				<image>
					<file>content/042780.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Santa Clara Pueblo, 1880. John K. Hillers, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 42780]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/132144.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Laguna pueblo, 1925 – 1945. T. Harmon Parkhurst, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 132144]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/140775.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Navajo winter and summer hogans, White River Canyon, Arizona. Bryce Elliot, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 140775]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/004360.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Santo Domingo Pueblo, view from Mission Roof, September 30, 1880. Bryce Elliot, Photo Archives, NMHM,<br>DCA 4360]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/031265.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Santo Domingo Pueblo, October 1, 1880. George C. Bennett, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 31265]]></caption>
				</image>
	        </slideshow>
		</slide>

		<!-- Beginning of Slide Spanish Colonization -->
		<!-- each section should have 4 slides with this data-->
		<!--<slide id="slide0.2">-->
			<!--<image>-->
				<!--<file>assets/panels/story_encounters_00.jpg</file>-->
			<!--</image>&lt;!&ndash; used for first slide that is just an image, &ndash;&gt;-->
		<!--</slide>-->
		<slide id="slide0-2" anchor="2">
			<title>Spanish Colonization</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
			<heading>In the late 1500s, Spanish land claims stretched from the tip of South America to Oregon and east 				to the Mississippi River.</heading>
			<description><![CDATA[
				<p>Before the Spanish crossed the Atlantic, they came to believe
				that they had been entrusted with a sacred mission. After
				seven centuries, they drove the Muslims from Spain in 1492.
				The same year, ships flying the spanish flag landed in the
				Americas. And soon Spanish soldiers and missionaries ruled
				vast new lands, brought tens of thousands of souls and
				subjects to God and King, and gathered unimaginable
				wealth. The Catholic Church and Spanish crown claimed it
				was their duty to bring salvation and civilization to all the
				peoples of this "New World." Their kingdom stretched
				across all the lands they occupied and stretches they had never seen.</p>
			]]></description>
			<quote><![CDATA[
				<p>"In the same name of the most Holy Trinity...I wish to take possession of
				the land today...in the vooice and name of the most Christian King,
				our lord, don Felipe, the Second of this name.... I take and seize one,
				two, and three times...without excepting anything and without
				limitation, with the meadows, glens, and their pastures and watering
				places...towns, cities, villas, castles, and strong houses and
				dwellings...the leaf on the mountains to the rock in the river to the leaf on the
				mountain."</p>
				<p class="align-right">- Don Juan de Oñate, April 30, 1598</p>
			]]></quote>
			<map id="2">
				<title>New Spain</title>
				<image><file>assets/map/map_02.png</file></image>
			</map>
			<slideshow id="slideshow0-2">
				<image>
					<file>content/Armada_galleass.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[An armada galeass, depicted in the anonymous Greenwich Cartoon. Public Domain]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/3a38351u.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Coronado’s March, Colorado, ca. 1897. Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/MexicoOrNewSpain.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Mexico of New Spain, 1777. Fray Angélico Chávez History Library, NMHM, DCA, Map Collection 7.2 1777]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/3a50528u.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Old mission church, New Mexico, built 1776 at Zuni, 1873. Timothy O’Sullivan, Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/031814.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Algodones, New Mexico. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 31814]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/Transparency-1.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Oñate Medallion. Courtesy of the Archdiocese of Santa Fe Collection in the Museum of International Folk Art, NMHM, DCA L1.1957.49]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/129403.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Oñate Inscription, August 18, 1940. Ralph H. Anderson, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 129403]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/014769.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Corpus Christi procession. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 14769]]></caption>
				</image>
			</slideshow>
		</slide>

		<!-- Beginning of Slide Louisiana Purchase -->
		<slide id="slide0-3" anchor="3">
			<title>Louisiana Purchase</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
			<heading>In the span of forty years, the vast Louisiana Territory was
			claimed, traded, or purchased by France, Spain, and
			the United States, and yet all the people living on the land were Native Americans.
			</heading>
			<description><![CDATA[
				France claimed the Louisians Territory in the late 1600s. The French
				sold much of the lands to Spain in 1763 to keep them
				from falling into the hands of the British. Forty years later,
				Emperor Napoleon of France persuaded Spain to return the
				territory to France, Within days, the French sold it to the
				United States, partly to raise money to fight the British.
				Beginning in 1803, the united States and Spain found
				themselves sharing a new border more than a thousand miles
				long, though neither nation knew exactly where that border
				was. Both claimed as much land as they could--Spain
				declared that Spanish territory stretched north to the
				Missouri River and met the Louisiana Territory there. The
				United States claimed that Louisiana reached west to the Rio
				Grande, including all of present-day Texas and much of New Mexico.
				The people who lived on the land generally had no
				part in deciding where one empire ended and the next began.
			]]></description>
			<quote><![CDATA[
				<p>"Is it not better that the opposite banks of the Mississippi should be
				settled by our own brethren and children than by strangers of
				another family?"</p>
				<p class="align-right">-Thomas Jefferson</p>
			]]></quote>
			<map id="3">
				<title>Louisiana Purchase</title>
				<image><file>assets/map/map_03.png</file></image>
			</map>
			<slideshow id="slideshow0-3">
				<image>
					<file>content/segesser_II.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Segesser Hide (depicting Spanish, Native and French conflict), History Collection, NMHM, DCA 11005/45<br>Museum Purchase]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/ct000654.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Louisiana (map of Louisiana Purchase), 1814. Fray Angélico Chávez History Library, NMHM, DCA, Map Collection 76.3 1814 (1804)]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/His-oo-san-chess.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[“His-oo-san-chees,” The Little Spaniard, 1834. Image from John L. Kessell, <span class="imageCaptionItalic">Kiva, Cross, and Crown: The Pecos Indians and New Mexico, 1540 – 1840</span>. Washington, DC: National Park Service, 1979. p. 231. Original by George Catlin, 1834]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/28-0206a.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Treaty between the United States of America and the French Republic ceding the province of Louisiana to the United States, April 30, 1803. Courtesy of the National Archives]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/3g03410u.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[<span class="imageCaptionItalic">War dance of the Sauks and Foxes</span>, 1825-1834. P. Rindisbacher, printed by C. Hullmandel, Courtesy of the<br>Library of Congress]]></caption>
					<caption><![CDATA[<span class="imageCaptionItalic">War dance of the Sauks and Foxes</span>, 1825 – 1834. P. Rindisbacher, printed by C. Hullmandel, Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
				</image>
				<image>
					<file>content/3g03254u.jpg</file>
					<caption><![CDATA[Thomas Jefferson, third president of the United States. Lithographed and published by H. Robinson, N.Y. & Washington, D.C., 1840 – 1851. Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
				</image>
			</slideshow>
		</slide>
	</slides>
</section>
	<!-- Beginning of Section Whose Nation -->
	<section id="section1">
		<title>Whose Nation</title> <!-- Main menu title -->
		<image><file>assets/story/section_title_two.png</file></image> <!-- used for section image title on bottom -->

		<slides>
			<!-- each section should have 4 slides with this data-->
			<!-- Beginning of Mexican-American War -->
			<slide id="slide1-0" anchor="0"><!-- used for first slide that is just an image, -->
				<image>
					<file>assets/panels/story_whose_nation_00.jpg</file>
				</image>
			</slide>
			<slide id="slide1-1" anchor="1">
				<title>Mexican-American War</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
				<heading>The boundary between the United States and Mexico was fixed by treaty in 1819, until Mexico and the United States went to war in 1846.</heading>
				<description><![CDATA[
					<p>For years after the Louisiana Purchase, the United States
					and Spain contested the boundary between them. Finally in
					1819, John Quincy Adams and Spanish envoy Luis de Onís
					negotiated a treaty that fixed the boundary all across the
					West. Both nations ratified the agreement, but it began to
					unravel almost immediately. Mexico won independence from
					Spain in 1821. Texas declared independence from Mexico in
					1836, and joined the Unite States nine years later. The new
					state of Texas claimed a large tract of land also claimed by Mexico.</p>
					<p>This boundary dispute touched off the Mexican-American
					War in 1846. The U.S. population was growing and pushing
					west. President James Polk envisioned a nation that
					stretched to the Pacific. In Mexico City, the government had
					grave difficulties, both politically and financially, sustaining
					such a large territory, including New Mexico. In 1846,
					Mexican and American soldiers clashed along the border, and
					within two years the boundary changed as U.S. troops
					defeated Mexico.</p>
				]]></description>
				<quote><![CDATA[
					<p>"Mexico has passed the boundary of the United States, has invaded
					our territory and shed American blood on Americans soil. She has
					proclaimed that hostilities have commenced, and that the two
					nations are at war."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-President James K. Polk</p>
					<p>"We are not only supposed to remain silent while our unjust
					neighbors make off with the lands which they had at first selected
					for themselves, but we must also pay them for earning and taking
					them and others as well, and finally we are expected to confess that
					they had the right to do all this."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-Manuel Crecencio Rejón</p>
				]]></quote>
				<!-- No Map Button on this slide -->
				<map id="">
					<title></title>
					<image><file></file></image>
				</map>
				<slideshow id="slideshow1-1">
					<image>
						<file>content/3b48557u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Battle of Cerro Cordo, April 18, 1847. Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/3b49849u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[The Battle of Sacramento, fought February 28, 1847. Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/3g02956u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Battle of Resaca de la Palma, May 9, 1846. Capture of General Vega by the gallant Captain May. Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/3g02955u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Landing of the American forces under General Scott, at Vera Cruz, March 9, 1847, ca.1847. Courtesy of the<br>Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/3a24796u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[President James K. Polk, 1845. Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/3a22346u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[General D. Antonio Lopez De Santa-Anna, president of the Republic of Mexico, ca. 1847. Courtesy of the<br>Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/3b09860u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[The Battle of Mexico, 1847. Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/BrilliantCharge.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[The Brilliant Charge of Captain May, 1846. Fray Angélico Chávez History Library, DCA, NMHM, Graphics Collection 3-89]]></caption>
					</image>
				</slideshow>
			</slide>
			<slide id="slide1-2" anchor="2">
				<title>Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
				<heading>For Mexico, the price of peace at the end of the Mexican-
					American War was a new boundary with the United
					States, and the loss of half of Mexico's territory.
				</heading>
				<description><![CDATA[
					<p>At the end of the Mexican-American War, factions within
					both the United States and Mexico had wildly different ideas
					about how large a price Mexico should pay for its loss. But
					the original area in dispute--a swath of land between the Rio
					Grande and Nueces River in present-day Texas--would not
					be nearly enough of a concession. Some U.S. interests hoped
					to erase the boundary between Mexico and the United
					States, annex the entire country, and end its existence as a
					separate nation. In the end, the two nations settled on an
					area of about 525,000 square miles, a little more than half of
					Mexico's territory. This land eventually became all of Texas,
					California, and Utah, most of New Mexico and Arizona, and parts
					of Colorado and Wyoming.</p>
					<p>Other disputes over boundaries grew from the wording of the
					treaty itself. Mexican citizens who chose to remain in the
					United States were guaranteed the right to "retain their
					property." If they chose American citizenship, they were
					entitled to "the free enjoyment of their liberty and
					property." But the boundaries of their property, legally and
					geographically, were another matter. The U.S. understood
					boundaries very differently than the Mexicans and Spanish
					before them.</p>
				]]></description>
				<quote><![CDATA[
					<p>"This must be a proud moment for you; no less proud for you than
					humiliating for us."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-Don Bernardo Couto to American negotiator Nicholas trist, at the signing
					of the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo, February 2, 1848</p>
					<p>"Could those Mexicans have seen into my heart at that moment,
					they would have known that my feeling of shame as an American was
					far stronger than theirs could have been as Mexicans. For though it
					would not have done for me to say so there, that was a thing for
					every right-minded American to be ashamed of, and I was of it."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-U.S. negotiator Nicholas Trist, reflecting on the treaty</p>
				]]></quote>
				<map id="5">
					<title>Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo</title>
					<image><file>assets/map/map_05.png</file></image>
				</map>
				<slideshow id="slideshow1-2">
					<image>
						<file>content/Disturnell1846.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Mapa de los Estados Unidos de Méjico, 1846. Fray Angélico Chávez History Library, NMHM, DCA,<br>Map Collection 7.2 1846]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/Treaty_48.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo, 1848. Courtesy of the National Archives]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/07635u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Campaign poster for Democratic nominee Zachary Taylor, the victorious Mexican War general, 1848. James Ackerman, Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/02914a.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Nicholas Philip Trist, 1855 – 1865. Brady-Handy Photograph Collection, Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
				</slideshow>
			</slide><!-- Beginning of Slide Godsden Purchase -->
			<slide id="slide1-3" anchor="3">
				<title>Godsden Purchase</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
				<heading>Five years after the Mexican-American War, the United
					States needed more land in the Southwest for railroad
					route to California. The U.S. made Mexico an offer it
					couldn't refuse.
				</heading>
				<description><![CDATA[
					<p>Boundaries established at the cost of blood and gold can still
					vanish quickly. Only five years after the Treaty of Guadalupe
					Hidalgo, the United States sent James Gadsden to Mexico to
					negociate a new boundary between the countries. Godsden's
					most important goal was to acquire an expanse an expanse of land across
					southern New Mexico and Arizona for railroad to the
					Pacific. The Mexican government was still in turmoil after the
					war with the United States and desperately in need of cash.
					The United States gained some 29,670 square miles of land
					for $10 million.</p>
					<p>The treaty solved another boundary issue. The new border
					between the two nations meant nothing to Apaches (Inde)
					and other native peoples, and they raided across northern
					Mexico and southwestern United States as they had for
					obligated the United States to protect Mexican citizens from
					these raids, and the cost rose into the millions. The Gadsden
					Treaty erased the new boundary between the United States
					and Mexico, at least in the matter of Apache (Inde) raiders
					crossing it as they headed south.</p>
				]]></description>
				<quote><![CDATA[
					<p>"The Mexican Republic agrees to designate the following as her true
					limits with the United States for the future....Begining in the Gulf
					of Mexico, three leagues from land, opposite the mouth of the Rio
					grande, as provided in the 5th article of the treaty of Guadalupe
					Hidalgo; thence, as defined in the said article, up the middle of that
					river..."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-Gadsden Purchase, 1853</p>
				]]></quote>
				<map id="7">
					<title>Gadsden Purchase</title>
					<image><file>assets/map/map_07.png</file></image>
				</map>
				<slideshow id="slideshow1-3">
					<image>
						<file>content/rr001730.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[1855 Pacific Railway Route Map, 1857. Courtesy of the Library of Congress, Geography and Map Division]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/089772.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Engine No. 2511, Southern Pacific R.R., last regular train on the Cloudcroft branch, 1847. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 89772]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/056152.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Unidentified Apache group. A. Frank Randall, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 56152]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/057237.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Mesilla restaurant, later La Pasta Restaurant. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 57237]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/122144.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[First San Albino Catholic Church, built 1852, under renovation, Mesilla, New Mexico, ca. 1885 – 1890, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 122144]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/036115.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Mescalero Apache Group, ca. 1906. H.F. Robinson, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 36115]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/056344.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Street Scene, Mesilla, New Mexico. New Mexico State Tourist Bureau, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 056344]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/028266.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Chiricahua Apache Indians. James N. Ffileong, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 28266]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/013808.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[“Mexican Family,” October 16, 1895. Martinez Collection, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 13808]]></caption>
					</image>
				</slideshow>
			</slide>
		</slides>
	</section>
	<!-- Beginning of Section Becoming New Mexico -->
	<section id="section2">
		<title>Becoming New Mexico</title> <!-- Main menu title -->
		<image><file>assets/story/section_title_three.png</file></image> <!-- used for section image title on bottom -->

		<slides>
			<!-- each section should have 4 slides with this data-->
			<!-- Beginning of Compromise of 1850 -->
			<slide id="slide2-0" anchor="0"><!-- used for first slide that is just an image, -->
				<image>
					<file>assets/panels/story_becoming_nm_00.jpg</file>
				</image>
			</slide>
			<slide id="slide2-1" anchor="1">
				<title>Compromise of 1850</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
				<heading>The question of slavery in the U.S. was a factor in
				settling a long-staning border dispute between Texas
				and New Mexico.
				</heading>
				<description><![CDATA[
					<p>The vast territory added to the United States at the end of
					the Mexican-American War immediately sparked controversy
					in Congress. Legislators knew that the territory would
					eventually divide into different states that would one day join
					the Union. But what would their new boundaries be, and
					would they join as slave states or free?</p>
					<p>One trade-off in this complicated mixture of compromises
					finally fixed the border between Texas and New Mexico. For
					decades, Texas had claimed land west to the Rio Grande. But
					Texas also was deep in debt. Texas agreed to drop its land
					claims north and west of its current borders and the federal
					government assumed the state's debts. The residents of the
					new Territory of New Mexico would decide for themselves
					whether to permit slavery. California entered the Union as a
					free state. Southern slaveholders put in place a new Fugitive
					slave Act that compelled law officers and other officials
					around the country to aid in the capture of runaway slaves.
					These compromises helped hold off open conflict between the
					North and South; that boundary would be crossed only a
					decade later.</p>
				]]></description>
				<quote><![CDATA[
					<p>"Both California and New Mexico are likely to come in as free; and
					therefore some degree of disappointment and surprise has resulted.
					In other words, it is obvious that the question which has so long
					harassed the country, and at some times very seriously alarmed the
					minds of wise and good men, has come upon us for fresh discussion;
					the question of slavery in these United States."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-Daniel Webster, speech in U.S. Senate, March 7, 1850</p>
				]]></quote>
				<!-- No Map Button on this slide -->
				<map id="6">
					<title>Compromise 1850</title>
					<image><file>assets/map/map_06.png</file></image>
				</map>
				<slideshow id="slideshow2-1">
					<image>
						<file>content/02601u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[<span class="imageCaptionItalic">Union</span>, a symbolic group portrait eulogizing recent legislative efforts, notably the Compromise of 1850, to preserve the Union, ca. 1852. Painted By Tompkins H. Matteson, engraved by Henry S. Sadd, Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/1847_Map.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Map of Mexico, including Yucatan and Upper California, 1847. Fray Angélico Chávez History Library, NMHM, DCA, Map Collection 7.2 1847a]]></caption>
					</image>
				</slideshow>
			</slide><!-- Beginning of Slide State Boundaries -->
			<slide id="slide2-2" anchor="2">
				<title>State Boundaries</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
				<heading>Economic interest, local customs, and political all
					influence state borders.
				</heading>
				<description><![CDATA[
					<p>New Mexico Territory once included present-day New
					Mexico and Arizona, and tracts of land that today are small
					parts of other southwestern states. From the founding of the
					territory in 1850, different interests tried to carve it up in
					different ways. Sixty-two years later, it joined the nation as
					the 47th state.</p>

					<p>In 1862 the Confederate army invaded the territory and tried
					to reorganize it along horizontal lines, with Arizona on the
					bottom and New Mexico occupying roughly the northern
					half. Roughly fifty years later, just as advocates for statehood
					had made progress toward joining the rest of the United
					States, politicians in Washington came up with a "jointure"
					proposal, which would have admitted Arizona and New
					Mexico as one big state. Across the rest of the country, some
					people hestitated to include New Mexicans within the
					boundaries of the United States. They were considered too
					Hispanic Catholic, spoke little English, and lived by different
					territorial situation as second-class citizenship, and
					pressured their fellow New Mexicans and the national
					government to put the state of New Mexico on the national map.</p>
				]]></description>
				<quote><![CDATA[
					<p>"Our Grandfathers had no idea of living in any other place except
					our own land, and I don't think it is right for us to do what were
					taught not to do."</p>

					<p class="align-right">-Navajo Leader Barboncito, to Gen. William Sherman, May 28, 1868</p>
				]]></quote>
				<map id="">
					<title></title>
					<image><file></file></image>
				</map>
				<slideshow id="slideshow2-2">
					<image>
						<file>content/NM-AZHorizontal.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[California, Territories of New Mexico and Utah, 1863. Fray Angélico Chávez History Library, NMHM, DCA, Map Collection 78.9 1863]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/015813.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Old Holbrook, Arizona, ca. 1883. Ben Wittick, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 15813]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/106180.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Surveillance aircraft patrolling the border along the Rio Grande, ca. 1950. New Mexico Magazine Collection,<br>Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 106180]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/013309.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Thomas B. Catron, ca. 1917. Wesley Bradfield, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 13309]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/140378.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[“Carload of Governors,” Herbert Hagerman, Miguel A. Otero, William T. Thornton, L. Bradford Prince. Aaron B. Craycraft, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 140378]]></caption>
					</image>
				</slideshow>
				
			</slide><!-- Beginning of Slide American Indian Policy -->
			<slide id="slide2-3" anchor="3">
				<title>American Indian Policy</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
				<heading>In New Mexico, people lived on the land in different
					ways, and some of these ways could not co-exist.
					Becoming New Mexico is partly a matter of working out
					these differences, by treaty, force, custom, and law.
				</heading>
				<description><![CDATA[
					<p>The Native peoples of the Southwest have lived and moved
					across the region's vast landscape for thousands of years.
					They exchanged goods, arts, and ideas with other Native
					peoples that spread still farther across the continent. And in
					the deserts, mountains, and river valleys of the Southwest,
					they fashioned several different ways of life--as
					agriculturalists, hunters, gatherers, raiders, and mixture of
					all. Their ways of life linked them to sacred places and
					familiar landscapes. But the boundaries of Native peoples
					had nothing to do with lines on map.</p>
					<p>The U.S. government's Indian policies meant a twofold
					change for many Native Americans. First they must give up
					their way of life that had no legal boundaries--surveyed,
					recorded, and known to all. And second, they must move
					within new boundaries--inside houses, on lots, near crop
					fields and garden plots, within the confines of the
					reservation. Native peoples and cultures perished within
					these new boundaries. A few such as Pueblos and Navajos
					(Diné) in New Mexico, found a way to stay on their
					traditional homelands, despite the new boundaries all around them.</p>
				]]></description>
				<quote><![CDATA[
					<p>"Our Grandfathers had no idea of living in any other place axcept
					our own land, and I don't think it is right for us to do what we were
					taught not to do."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-Navajo Leader Barboncito, to Gen. William Sherman, May 28, 1868</p>
				]]></quote>
				<map id="">
					<title></title>
					<image><file></file></image>
				</map>
				<slideshow id="slideshow2-3">
					<image>
						<file>content/3b45614u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Near the base of Old Shiprock: Two Navajo Indians on horses with butte in background, ca. 1914. Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/05081u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Pueblos bring first protest since Lincoln: Four Pueblo men (L – R) Santiago Naranjo, Waihusing, James Miller, and Jesus Baca, January 15, 1923. Underwood & Underwood, Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/016038.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[“Navajo Woman Weaving a Blanket,” ca. 1980 – 1990. Ben Wittick, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 16038]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/160902.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[General William Tecumseh Sherman. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 160902]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/009581.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Old Mesilla plaza, New Mexico, ca. 1920. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 9581]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/048716.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Barboncito, Chief of the Navajo Tribe in New Mexico. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 48716]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/016482.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[At Supplee’s Ranch & Trading Store near Wingate. Ben Wittick, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 16482]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/045814.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Group of Ute and Jicarilla Indians including Agent W. F. M. Army, ca. 1868. Nicholas Brown, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 45814]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/028539.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Fort Sumner, New Mexico Street View, ca. 1866. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 28539]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/016468.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Navajo loom and hogan, ca. 1950. Ben Wittick, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 16468]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/036599.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[A.W. Cougar & Co., ca. 1884. Mary Lou Skinner, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 36599]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/028535.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Navajo scouts waiting to be paid at Fort Wingate, ca. 1886. Lynn Baily (U.S. Army Signal Corps.), Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 28535]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/05084u.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Group of Pueblo Indians photographed at the U.S. Capitol, January 23, 1923. National Photo Company, Courtesy of the Library of Congress]]></caption>
					</image>
				</slideshow>
			</slide>
		</slides>
	</section>
	<!-- Beginning of Section Homelands -->
	<section id="section3">
		<title>Homelands</title> <!-- Main menu title -->
		<image><file>assets/story/section_title_four.png</file></image> <!-- used for section image title on bottom -->

		<slides>
			<!-- each section should have 4 slides with this data-->
			<!-- Beginning of Taos Rebellion -->
			<slide id="slide3-0" anchor="0"><!-- used for first slide that is just an image, -->
				<image>
					<file>assets/panels/story_becoming_nm_00.jpg</file>
				</image>
			</slide>
			<slide id="slide3-1" anchor="1">
				<title>Taos Rebellion</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
				<heading>What if a Mexican town doesn't agree to become a U.S.
					town, even after the U.S. Army defeats Mexico in battle?
				</heading>
				<description><![CDATA[
					<p>By the 1840's, Taos had been a crossroads for
					centuries--between Native people, Spanish and later
					Mexican settlers, and trappers and traders from France and
					the United States. Some U.S. citizens settled there, started
					businesses, married local women, and raised families. The
					invasion of U.S. troops during the Mexican-American War
					redrew the boundaries around Taos. This time, hundreds of
					Pueblo and Mexican people saw a threat to their way of life
					and rose up to defend their homelands. On January 19, 1847,
					the Rebels killed the new governor of the New Mexico
					territory, Charles Bent, and several others.</p>
					<p>Sent to put down the revolt, U.S. Army Col. Sterling Price
					said, "It appeared to be the object of the insurrectionists to
					put to death every...[m]an who had accepted office under
					the American government." Price and his soldiers
					surrounded many of the rebels and their families in the
					church at Taos Pueblo and killed roughly 150 people.
					Approximately twenty rebel leaders were captured, tried,
					and hanged. Thought they were fighting against the soldiers
					and officials of another country, they were convicted of
					murder and treason. Can men defending their country be
					traitors?</p>
				]]></description>
				<quote><![CDATA[
					<p>"I received information from a Mexican friendly to our Government
					that a conspiracy was on foot among the native Mexicans, having for
					its object the expulsion of the United States troops and civil
					authorities from the Territory."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-Charles Bent, December 26, 1846</p>
				]]></quote>
				<slideshow id="slideshow3-1">
					<image>
						<file>content/104445.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Fernando de Taos, New Mexico, ca. 1885. George E. Mellen, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 104445]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/052337.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Congressman Manuel Luján and President Richard Nixon, 1971. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 52337]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/04449.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Mission Ruins, Taos, New Mexico, ca. 1935. T. Harmon Parkhurst, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 4449]]></caption>
					</image>
				</slideshow>
				<!-- No Map Button on this slide -->
				<map id="">
					<title></title>
					<image><file></file></image>
				</map>
			</slide>
			<slide id="slide3-2" anchor="2">
				<title>Land Grants</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
				<heading>Over centuries, custom and tradition often evolve into
					law. Land grants in New Mexico reflect different
					customs, obligations, measurements, and legal traditions
					across the landscape.
				</heading>
				<description><![CDATA[
					<p>The Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo stated clearly that the
					people who owned land that would become part of the United
					States had an indisputable right to their property. The way
					some of these former Mexicans owned their land was
					different than in the United States, and opened the door to a
					wave of disputes that continues to this day.</p>
					<p>In 1848, some communities across New Mexico owned tracts
					of land in common--for the benefit of all of their members.
					These common lands were part of land grants given to
					citizens first by the Spanish king and later by the government
					of Mexico. By law and custom, a piece of paper spelling out
					the boundaries of common lands was not the sole key to
					ownership, and often didn't exist. More important was a
					community's understanding of the extent of its lands, and
					the decisions of local leaders and councils over the years.
					These ways of owning and describing land counted for little
					in the U.S. legal system. Lawyers, business interests, and
					speculators challenged these land grants in courts and
					government offices. Within sixty years, roughly 90 percent of
					the common lands in New Mexico no longer belonged to their
					communities.</p>
				]]></description>
				<quote><![CDATA[
					<p>"The law now in force, requiring the surveyor general to ascertain
					origin, nature, character, and extent of all claims to land under
					the laws, usages, and customs of Spain and Mexico...after thirteen
					years' experience, has failed utterly to accomplish the purposes
					intended by it."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-New Mexico Surveyor John A. Clark, 1867</p>
				]]></quote>
				<map id="">
					<title></title>
					<image><file></file></image>
				</map>
				<slideshow id="slideshow3-2">
					<image>
						<file>content/Landgrants1920(s).jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[New Mexico, 1920. Fray Angélico Chávez History Library, NMHM, DCA Map Collection 78.9 E 1920s]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/005526.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Irrigation acequia, New Mexico, 1935. T. Harmon Parkhurst, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 5526]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/068820.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Sheep threshing wheat in northern New Mexico, using methods similar to those used in Spain over two hundred years earlier, ca. 1925 – 1945. T. Harmon Parkhurst, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 68820]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/068901.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Typical scene of sheep grazing on common lands in northern New Mexico, 1935. T. Harmon Parkhurst,<br>Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 68901]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/061298.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Dry-farmed field near Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1909. Jesse Nusbaum, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 61298]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/022697.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Winnowing wheat, Picuris Pueblo, New Mexico, ca. 1935. T. Harmon Parkhurst, Photo Archives, NMHM,<br>DCA 22697]]></caption>
					</image>
				</slideshow>
			</slide><!-- Beginning of Slide Mesilla-A Town in Two Countries -->
			<slide id="slide3-3" anchor="3">
				<title>Mesilla-A Town in Two Countries</title><!-- bottom nav button title -->
				<heading>Between 1850, and 1854, both Mexico and the United
					States claimed Mesilla. Most residents hoped to remain
					Mexican, but internationally the town was in no man's
					land. By treaty and purchase, the Mexican and U.S.
					governments decided that Mesilla should join the United States.
				</heading>
				<description><![CDATA[
					<p>On March 1, 1850, Rafeal Ruelas and roughly sixty other men
					and women founded the village of Mesilla, Mexico. Most of
					the founding families livec on land that became part if the
					United States after the Mexican-American War. They
					established Mesilla to remain Mexican, but they lived in a
					land of fluid boundaries.</p>
					<p>Following the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo, the map that
					surveyors used to help determine the boundary between the
					United States and Mexico had a serious error. Both nations
					claimed the fertile Mesilla Valley. But the valley was an ideal
					route for a railroad across the Southwest, and powerful
					interests in the U.S. wanted that railroad. With the
					Gadsden Purchase in 1853, also called the Treaty of Mesilla,
					the boundary between the two nations moved west, and the
					people of Mesilla found themselves in the United States
					again.</p>
					<p>In 1862, Confederate troops swept through the valley during
					the Civil War and declared Mesilla the capital of the new
					Territory of Arizona. Union troops soon pushed back the
					Confederate army, and the new territory survived less than
					two years, shorter the the original town of Mesilla, Mexico.
					Through this and more, the town survives, and mant of
					Mesilla's 2,000 residents are descendants of the original
					founding families.</p>
				]]></description>
				<quote><![CDATA[
					<p>"We didn't cross the border, the border crossed us."</p>
					<p class="align-right">-José Antonio Burciaga, a Chicano writer, muralista, actor and activist,
					and a seminal figure in the Chicano Movement of the 1970s.</p>
				]]></quote>
				<map id="">
					<title></title>
					<image><file></file></image>
				</map>
				<slideshow id="slideshow3-3">
					<image>
						<file>content/NM-MAG-Border-Patrol.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Surveillance aircraft patrolling the border along the Rio Grande, ca. 1950. New Mexico Magazine Collection, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/056344.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Street Scene, Mesilla, New Mexico, 1961. New Mexico State Tourist Bureau, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 056344]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/009581.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Old Mesilla plaza, New Mexico, ca. 1920. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 9581]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/014299.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[The Catholic Church of San Albino (built 1852), Mesilla, New Mexico, ca. 1881. Striles & Burke, Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 14299]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/009588.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Private home of Paul Taylor. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 9588]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/14578.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Plaza, Mesilla, New Mexico. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 14578]]></caption>
					</image>
					<image>
						<file>content/009591.jpg</file>
						<caption><![CDATA[Paul Taylor’s House. Photo Archives, NMHM, DCA 9591]]></caption>
					</image>
				</slideshow>
			</slide>
		</slides>
	</section>
</sections>
